https://www.harrowbylane.org.uk/privacy/

Personal Data
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the GDPR).
Data Controller
Within the Methodist Church The Trustees for Methodist Church Purposes (TMCP) and the Connexional Team act jointly as data controllers (contact details below). This means they decide how your personal data is processed and for what purposes
Data Processors – how do we process your personal data?
Data processors are members of the church who hold and process personal data on behalf of the church.  Our obligations under the GDPR are met by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use personal data for the following purposes: –
to administer membership and pastoral records;
to maintain our financial accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid);
to provide news and information about events, activities and services at the church;
to fundraise and promote the interests of the church;
to manage volunteers;
to provide contact details of officers and others with specific responsibilities to the Grantham and Vale of Belvoir Circuit, Nottingham and Derby District of the Methodist Church
What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Data Processing is carried out by the church as a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –
the processing relates only to members or former members or those who have regular contact with the church
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent or
processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement; or
explicit consent of the data subject has been given.
Sharing personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members, to offer pastoral care and support for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties with your consent.
How long do we keep data?
We retain data for these specific records on the following basis:.  Retention periods of other records  can be found at          https://www.methodist.org.uk/static/rm/document_retention.pdf
Record Type
Retention Period1
Membership rolls
Indefinitely but reviewed annually
Members, adherents and friends contact details
Indefinitely but reviewed annually
Junior Church/ Sunday School rolls , registers
Whilst church is in use
Accident Books
3 years from the date of the last entry (or, if the accident involves a child/ young adult, then until that person reaches the age of 21)
Complaints (non -safeguarding)
3 years after resolution of complaint
Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –
The right to request a copy of the personal data which the Church holds about you (a Subject Access Request or SAR ;
The right to request that the Church corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased when it is no longer necessary for the Church  to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to object to the processing of personal data;
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.
Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Church Council secretary
You may also contact the the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
The Methodist Church
25 Marylebone Road
London  NW1 5JR
0207 4865502
Trustees for Methodist Church Purposes
Central Buildings, Oldham Street
Manchester
M1 1JQ
